Yoon Kim

Frontend Developer

Yoon is a versatile frontend developer with a passion for finding creative and efficient solutions to build a user-friendly product based on her knowledge in UI/UX design and programming skills. She has strong fundamentals and experiences in frontend technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and modern frameworks including React, Next.js and Vue.

Work Experience



1 yr 10 mos

Software Developer

Dec 2022 - Present

- · Working on building a frontend of a ReFi dApp called Ecoverse, a metaverse representing real-world forests based on the current forestry operations data all around the world.
- Building a web3 utility function where the dApp handles all web3 related calls including connecting to the wallet, signing transactions.

Junior Software Developer

June 2021 - Dec 2022

- Built a forest products trading app using Next.js, React, Typescript, Tailwind CSS, Prisma, GraphQL, and PostgreSQL
- Built a NFT staking page where users can stake or unstake their NFTs and claim rewards earned during the staking period by interacting with the smart contract using Vue.js and web3.js.
- Led the credit scoring oracle dApp project, built on NEAR Protocol, where users can get their credit score based on their crypto and fiat financial history.

Software Developer Intern

Apr 2021 - June 2021

- Redesigned and rebuilt BalloonBox's website to better represent company's values and enhance functionality and user experience.
- · Participated in building a new feature of a Fintech app using React JS that enables users to make payments with specific vendors.

Featured Projects

ScoreBox Nov 2022

- Built a frontend of the credit scoring dApp where users can calculate their credit score based on their crypto financial history using Next.js, TypeScript, Taillwiind CSS.
- · Integrated with both MetaMask & NEAR wallet for address fetching using ethers and NEAR JS API.

P IcePik Apr 2021- Jan 2022

- Responsible for developing the brand identity and designing the user flows using Figma, ensuring a consistent and intuitive user experience throughout the app.
- Built reusable and testable UI components using Next.js, TypeScript, and Tailwind CSS, which helped optimize performance and ensure code quality.

yoonthecoder.com

in linkedin.com/in/imyoonkim

@yoonthecoder

Skills & Tools

Development

HTML5, CSS3/SCSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Vue.js, React, Next.js, Node.js, Redux, Prisma, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, Web3.js, ethers, Git

Project Management

Jira, Github Project, Agile

UX/UI Design

Figma, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

Education

British Columbia Institute of Technology

Diploma, New Media Design and Web Development (with distinction)

- · Learned and developed skills in Web Development, UX/UI Design, Project Management, Digital Marketing and more.
- Improved on collaboration skills through working in various design and development team projects.

Sungshin Women's University

Bachelor's degree, English/Language Arts Teacher Education 2015-2018

Honors & Awards

Best Use of NEAR Protocol & Covalent

Issued by ETH San Francisco Nov 2022

 Attended ETHSF, the biggest web3 & blockchain hackathon in the history of Web3 and built a credit scoring dApp that calculates users' credit scores based on their crypto financial history and uploads them on the blockchain.